<Type Name="VisualType" FullName="Gdk.VisualType">
  <TypeSignature Language="C#" Maintainer="miguel" Value="public enum VisualType" />
  <TypeSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".class public auto ansi sealed VisualType extends System.Enum" />
  <AssemblyInfo>
    <AssemblyName>gdk-sharp</AssemblyName>
    <AssemblyPublicKey>
    </AssemblyPublicKey>
  </AssemblyInfo>
  <ThreadSafetyStatement>Gtk# is thread aware, but not thread safe; See the <link location="node:gtk-sharp/programming/threads">Gtk# Thread Programming</link> for details.</ThreadSafetyStatement>
  <Base>
    <BaseTypeName>System.Enum</BaseTypeName>
  </Base>
  <Attributes>
    <Attribute>
      <AttributeName>GLib.GType(typeof(Gdk.VisualTypeGType))</AttributeName>
    </Attribute>
  </Attributes>
  <Docs>
    <summary>Describe the how pixel values are converted into RGB values for display.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <para>
        Visuals are a very important concept that is often
        overlooked. Roughly, a visual defines the memory
        representation that a piece of hardware uses to store the
        contents of an image. X supports different kinds of visuals to
        suit the different kinds of hardware out there.
      </para>
      <para>
        Some of this information comes from Federico Mena's excellent
        "X Concepts" document from http://www.nuclecu.unam.mx/~federico/docs/x-concepts.
      </para>
    </remarks>
  </Docs>
  <Members>
    <Member MemberName="DirectColor">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="DirectColor" />
      <MemberSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".field public static literal valuetype Gdk.VisualType DirectColor = int32(5)" />
      <MemberType>Field</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>Gdk.VisualType</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters />
      <Docs>
        <summary>DirectColor visuals use RGB encoding, with a
        correction palette.</summary>
        <remarks>
          <para>
            TrueColor visuals store explicit RGB values for every
            pixel, instead of storing a single value like indexed
            visuals.
          </para>
          <para>
            The values in a direct color visual go through an
            indirection step before being sent to the display. Each of
            the R/G/B values you specify is an index in separate
            tables, and those tables contain a translated value. So an
            RGB triplet gets translated into an R'G'B' triplet,
            i.e. the three tables together define an f(r, g, b) -&gt;
            (r', g', b') function. For most purposes, your tables will
            be filled by the identity function and you will get
            linearly increasing intensity values for each of the RGB
            channels. Things can become quite interesting, however,
            when you modify the tables to have a nonlinear mapping. If
            you fill them using an exponential function, you can do
            color correction on hardware
          </para>
        </remarks>
      </Docs>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="Grayscale">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="Grayscale" />
      <MemberSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".field public static literal valuetype Gdk.VisualType Grayscale = int32(1)" />
      <MemberType>Field</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>Gdk.VisualType</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters />
      <Docs>
        <summary>Grayscale visuals are used for displays that use a single channel of color information.</summary>
        <remarks>
            Black and white or grayscale monitors (including amber and
            green monitors) may use this type of visual. These visuals
            can be either static gray or grayscale.
        </remarks>
      </Docs>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="PseudoColor">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="PseudoColor" />
      <MemberSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".field public static literal valuetype Gdk.VisualType PseudoColor = int32(3)" />
      <MemberType>Field</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>Gdk.VisualType</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters />
      <Docs>
        <summary>An indexed color visual, where colors can change.</summary>
        <remarks>
          Pseudo color visuals are those in which you can change the
          actual colors that the indexes correspond to. Each index
          maps to an RGB triplet that defines the color that will be
          displayed on the screen. You can change these RGB triplets
          for each index. Pseudo color visuals are very common in
          graphics cards. Graphics cards with 256 colors that you can
          change, for example, VGA cards, are of the pseudo color
          type.
        </remarks>
      </Docs>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="StaticColor">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="StaticColor" />
      <MemberSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".field public static literal valuetype Gdk.VisualType StaticColor = int32(2)" />
      <MemberType>Field</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>Gdk.VisualType</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters />
      <Docs>
        <summary>An indexed color visual, where colors can not be changed.</summary>
        <remarks>
           Static color visuals are those in which you cannot change
           the actual colors that the indexes correspond to (a static
           palette). Remember the old CGA cards with four fixed colors
           in graphics mode?  These could be considered of the static
           color type.
        </remarks>
      </Docs>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="StaticGray">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="StaticGray" />
      <MemberSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".field public static literal valuetype Gdk.VisualType StaticGray = int32(0)" />
      <MemberType>Field</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>Gdk.VisualType</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters />
      <Docs>
        <summary>Static gray visuals are those in which you cannot change the gray intensities of the hardware.</summary>
        <remarks>
	  Plain monochrome (B/W) displays or fixed 4-gray displays may
          be of the static gray kind. Grayscale visuals are those in
          which you can change the gray intensities used by the
          hardware. Exotic 12-bit grayscale displays (as used for
          medical visualization) that let you change the gray
          intensities may be of the grayscale type.
        </remarks>
      </Docs>
    </Member>
    <Member MemberName="TrueColor">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="TrueColor" />
      <MemberSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".field public static literal valuetype Gdk.VisualType TrueColor = int32(4)" />
      <MemberType>Field</MemberType>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>Gdk.VisualType</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters />
      <Docs>
        <summary>True color visuals use the exact RGB values you specified
        for a pixel</summary>
        <remarks>
          <para>
            TrueColor visuals store explicit RGB values for every
            pixel, instead of storing a single value like indexed
            visuals.
          </para>
          <para>
           TrueColor visuals map the RGB into the screens RGB values
           without any changes.  There is no transformation applied to
           it.
          </para>
        </remarks>
      </Docs>
    </Member>
  </Members>
</Type>
